<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Gary Haran</title>
 <link href="http://garyharan.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://garyharan.com/"/>
 <updated>2010-04-05T10:45:47-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://garyharan.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Gary Haran</name>
   <email>gary.haran@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>5 Actions To Make You Happier</title>
   <link href="http://garyharan.com//2010/04/04/clean-slate-clean-pants.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://garyharan.com//2010/04/04/clean-slate-clean-pants</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;5 Actions To Make You Happier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;April 4th Montreal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;gist&quot;&gt;Happiness is not universally quantifiable but money is.  Our brains races towards quantifiable goals at the expense of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Reduce your commute time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is not measurable in the same way that salary is.  There are no metrics for what makes us happy so we tend to race towards what is quantifiable &amp;#8211; high salary.  If we spend just a little more quality time away with family and friends our lives are richer and more fulfilling.  Sometimes taking a lower paying job makes sense if it means you spend more time doing what you love.  If the money you make does not help you do what you love you&amp;#8217;re a sucker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commuting is a sad side effect of many jobs and sadly the higher the salary the more commute time we&amp;#8217;re willing to do each day.  Finding ways to shave off commute time has a proven benefit as measure by this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cces.ethz.ch/agsam2009/panels/AGSAM2009_panel_mobility_Stutzer.pdf&quot;&gt;research (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Remove Small Frustrations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start every day by putting a kettle on to make some tea.  The kettle I used to have wouldn&amp;#8217;t turn on properly. I had to jiggle the button and it sometimes turned off on me.  I &lt;strong&gt;wrote down&lt;/strong&gt; that it frustrated me.  The next time I was at the store for something unrelated I spend 40$ on a beautiful aluminum kettle that starts my day better than ever before.  Whenever I look at this new kettle I smile and think about how I used to be frustrated but now it&amp;#8217;s all pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What frustrates you repeatedly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2009/06/what-makes-us-happy/7439/&quot;&gt;Harvard University study started in 1937&lt;/a&gt; and spanned 72 years determined that sports (or play of some kind) can relieve daily frustrations and make you happier overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe having a set of darts at home is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Have Regular Meetups With People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would doubling your income make you happier?  Well it turns out that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2010/03/30/opinion/30brooks.html&quot;&gt;regularly seeing people&lt;/a&gt; provide the same benefit as doubling your salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Have a Drink With Co-Workers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who occasionally have a single drink after work with colleagues make &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zevgroup.com/socialdrinking.html&quot;&gt;more money&lt;/a&gt; on average than those who do not drink at all.  It turns out that socializing is a happiness boost too so you&amp;#8217;re winning on all aspects here.  If you&amp;#8217;re smart you&amp;#8217;ll take the extra money and spend it on a well deserved vacation but that&amp;#8217;s for another list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>